JIGAR PATEL

https://www.linkedin.com/in/8jigarpatel/ | 8.jigar.patel@gmail.com

Experienced Software Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Has experience in different languages, most recently with a focus on web technologies, particularly C#, ASP.NET & ASP.NET Core (MVC & Web API), SQL, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, WebAPI, Angular, React, ExpressJS, and TailwindCSS.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Applied Systems Canada, Remote - Canada

Software Developer III

Database Consultants Australia (DCA), Melbourne, Australia

Senior Software Developer

Software Developer

Graduate Developer

[May 2022 - Current]

[September 2021 - May 2022] [July 2018 - August 2021]

[March 2017 - June 2018]

Responsibilities

- Writing and modifying software code to implement new features and fix defects.
- Integrating software with external services such as Payment Gateways and Address Search services.
- Investigating and rectifying codebase to enhance overall software performance.
 - Improved application performance by 20% with code optimization
- Writing notes for code modifications and upgrade notes for software deployment.
- Discussing and analysing technical challenges and possible solutions with team.
- Liaising with team members to convert user requirements into system requirements and develop required specification for software components.
- Assisting new team members to better understand software product and underlying codebase.
- Peer review code modifications to ensure requirements are addressed in maintainable and efficient manner.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages and Frameworks
 - C#, ASP .NET & ASP .NET Core (MVC & Web API), ExpressJS, SQL, React, Angular, Angular JS, HTML, CSS, TS, JS, TailwindCSS
- Other Technologies and Tools
 - Git, Jenkins for CI/CD, OWASP ZAP for vulnerability scanning, Sort Site for Accessibility testing, and understanding of containerization platform (Docker / Kubernetes)
- 6+ years of experience in Software Development working mainly with Web-based applications and APIs.
- Experience working with the project teams and vendors to determine the appropriate functional requirements for the project.
- Strong understanding of SDLC and Project life cycle.
- Experience in CI/CD pipelines and understanding of containerization platform (Docker / Kubernetes).
- Demonstrated ability to provide guidance and training to junior developers.
- Understanding of OWASP ZAP to perform vulnerability scans on Web-based applications.
- Self-motivated with excellent problem solving, analytical and communication skills with ability to work within team or individually.

EDUCATION

Master of Science (Network Systems) - Swinburne University of Tech., Melbourne, Australia [2014 - 2016]

Maintained 3.83 GPA (Grade Point Average)

Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Engineering), LDR-ITR, Gujarat, India

[2010 - 2014]

Maintained 8.36 CGPA (Cumulative Grade Point Average)

CERTIFICATIONS

MCSA: Web Applications [Certified 2020] MCSD: App Builder [Certified 2020] [Certified 2022]

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate